But seriously, we all say we hate this crap. The question is whether you're willing to make a personal sacrifice to change it. I don't mean giving up the Internet. I mean changing the way you click, because clicking is a public act. It's no longer the case that a few powerful elites control all the media and the rest of us are just passive receivers. Increasingly, we're all the media. I used to think, oh, okay, I get dressed up, I put on a lot of makeup, I go on television, I talk about the news. That is a public act of making media. And then I go home and I browse the web and I'm reading Twitter, and that's a private act of consuming media. I mean, of course it is. I'm in my pajamas. Wrong. Everything we blog, everything we Tweet, and everything we click is a public act of making media. We are the new editors. We decide what gets attention based on what we give our attention to. That's how the media works now. There's all these hidden algorithms that decide what you see more of and what we all see more of based on what you click on, and that in turn shapes our whole culture. Over three out of five Americans think we have a major incivility problem in our country right now, but I'm going to guess that at least three out of five Americans are clicking on the same insult-oriented, rumor-mongering trash that feeds the nastiest impulses in our society. In an increasingly noisy media landscape, the incentive is to make more noise to be heard, and that tyranny of the loud encourages the tyranny of the nasty. It does not have to be that way. It does not. We can change the incentive. For starters, there are two things we can all do. First, don't just stand by the sidelines when you see someone getting hurt. If someone is being abused online, do something. Be a hero. This is your chance. Speak up. Speak out. Be a good person. Drown out the negative with the positive. And second, we've got to stop clicking on the lowest-common-denominator, bottom-feeding linkbait. If you don't like the 24/7 all Kardashian all the time programming, you've got to stop clicking on the stories about Kim Kardashian's sideboob. I know you do it. (Applause) You too, apparently. I mean, really, same example: if you don't like politicians calling each other names, stop clicking on the stories about what one guy in one party called the other guy in the other party. Clicking on a train wreck just pours gasoline on it. It makes it worse, the fire spreads. Our whole culture gets burned. If what gets the most clicks wins, then we have to start shaping the world we want with our clicks, because clicking is a public act. So click responsibly. Thank you. (Applause)
Pero en serio, todos decimos que odiamos esta basura, la pregunta es si uno está dispuesto a hacer un sacrificio personal para cambiarlo. No me refiero a renunciar a la Internet, me refiero a cambiar la forma de hacer clic, porque hacer clic es un acto público. Ya no es el caso, que unas pocas élites poderosas controlan todos los medios y el resto de nosotros somos solo receptores pasivos. Cada vez más, somos todos los medios de comunicación. Solía pensar, oh, está bien, me visto, me pongo mucho maquillaje, voy de la televisión, hablo de la noticias. Eso es un acto público de hacer los medios de comunicación. Luego me voy a casa y navego por la web y leo Twitter, y eso es un acto privado de consumo de medios. Quiero decir, claro que lo es, estoy en mi pijamas. Error. Todo lo que blogueamos, todo lo que tuiteamos, y a todo a lo que hacemos clic es un acto público de estar en los medios. Somos los nuevos editores. Nosotros decidimos lo que llama la atención con base a lo que le damos atención. Así es como funcionan los medios ahora. Hay todos estos algoritmos ocultos que deciden lo que se ve más y lo que todos vemos más basados en lo que hacemos clic, que a su vez da forma a toda nuestra cultura. Tres de 5 estadounidenses piensan que tenemos un grave problema de falta de civismo en nuestro país actualmente, pero voy a suponer que, al menos, 3 de cada 5 estadounidenses están haciendo clic en el mismo insulto, difundiendo el rumor que alimenta los impulsos más repugnantes de nuestra sociedad. En un panorama mediático cada vez más ruidoso, el incentivo es hacer más ruido para ser oído, y esa tiranía de lo escandaloso alienta la tiranía de lo desagradable. No tiene por qué ser así. No tiene por qué. Podemos cambiar el incentivo. Para empezar, hay dos cosas que todos podemos hacer. Primero, no aislarse cuando ven a alguien haciendo daño. Si alguien es víctima de acoso en línea, ¡hagan algo! Sean héroes. Esta es su oportunidad. Hablen. Hablen. Sean buenas personas. Ahoguen lo negativo con lo positivo. Y en segundo lugar, dejemos de hacer clic en el más bajo-común-denominador del botón que alimenta al enlace señuelo. Si no les gusta 'toda la programación todo Kardashian 24/7', tienen que dejar de hacer clic en las historias sobre las fotos de los senos de Kim Kardashian. Sé que lo hacen. (Aplausos) Ud. también, al parecer. De verdad, el mismo ejemplo: si no les gustan los políticos que se andan insultando dejen de hacer clic en las historias acerca del tipo de un partido que insultó al del otro partido. Hacer clic en un choque de trenes solo vierte gasolina. Hacen que sea peor, el fuego se extiende. Toda nuestra cultura se quema. Si el que obtiene el mayor número de clics gana, entonces tenemos que empezar a dar forma al mundo que queremos con nuestros clics, porque hacer clic es un acto público. Entonces hagan clic en forma responsable. Gracias. (Aplausos)